#### Akmal Rivai

Phone: 085889931500 | <u>akmalrivai29@gmail.com</u> | https://www.linkedin.com/in/akmal-rivai-320202201/

## Depok – Jawa Barat

I am Akmal Rivai, a graduate of Informatic Engineering from Indraprasta University in 2020. I bring with me several years of experience as a Quality Assurance Freelancer at Palastri Karya Optima, Risk Analyst at PT Bank Rakyat Indonesia (Persero) Tbk and currently as Software Quality Assurance also as Scrum Master and Product Manager at PT Bank Rakyat Indonesia (Persero) Tbk. With my educational background, I am confident that my qualification and skills could make significant contributions to the company. I am a person who can work well as part of a team and on my own. I am also hardworking, and eager to learn.

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Indraprasta PGRI University**

2016 - 2020

Information technology, IPK: 3,11/4.00

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

PT Bank Rakyat Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.

Jakarta

Selatan Software Quality Assurance

August 2022–Present

- Create Test Scenario/Test Case
- Do testing manual
- Do regression test
- Do end to end test
- Do test API with Postman
- Create update and execution ticket to Jira
- Tracking Bug and create bugs report
- SIT/UAT

Scrum Master

Januari 2024 – Present

- Implementing Scrum Value, Pillar & between product, business & IT divison
- Optimize collaboration between product, business and engineering
- Set up agile culture for engineering

- Create Flowchart
- Create Product Requirement Document (PRD)
- Prioritize product Backlog
- Ensure deliverable project on time and within scope
- Work closely with stakeholders and developers

## Risk Analyst

*August* 2021 – *August* 2022

- Create a rule base to be used as a parameter in the dashboard
- Create a Business Requirement Document (BRD) if there is a request to make a new dashboard or tools
- Do product analysis using internal dashboards to know product Performance and growth every month
- Make e-commerce report ( Issuer & Acquirer) every quarter
- Monitoring account leak through Jira
- Processing data using Excel
- Analysis data fraud through mastercardconnect and Visa analytic platform

## Palastri Karya Optima (Freelancer)

Jakarta

Selatan Quality Assurance Manual

October 2022 – December

#### 2022

- Create Test Scenario
- Create Test Case
- Do testing manual
- Do regression test
- Do test API with Postman
- Upload file to Jira

### **CERTIFICATIONS & LICENSES**

- Python Data Science (Sanbercode November 2021)
- Software Quality Assurance Tester Automation User Interface Testing (Jago QA September 2022)
- Software Quality Assurance Tester Automation API Testing (Jago QA September 2022)
- Software Quality Assurance Tester Manual API Testing (Jago QA September 2022)
- Machine Learning Developer (IDcamp Dicoding Desember 2023)

### **SKILL**

Hardskill: Laravel PHP Framework, Automation cypress Testing, Postman for API Testing, Manual Testing, Test Execution, Regression Test, End to End Test, MySQL, CSS, Java, JavaScript, PHP, HTML, Microsoft Excel, Powerpoint, JIRA, Confluence.

**Softskill**: Problem Solving, Team Working, Public Relation, Analytical Skill, Communication, Time Management.

Nomes Sert Quade : 552912020008307 Complete Serial Municipal

51 066992

# Universitas Indraprasta PGRI Indraprasta PGRI University Memberikan Ijazah kepada has awardad ika certificate ia

### Akmal Rivai

Tempot dan tanggal lahir Place and Date of Birth Nature Pakok Mahanisma Student Number

201643502879

Program Pendidikan Educativa Programme

46

Education Programs
Falsalton
Forestly
Program Stedi
Staff Programme
Tanggal Yudislam
Graduation Date

Stretz Satu (St) Hodespredute Teknik dan Ilmu Komputer forgierring and Computer Stevans Teknik Informatika Advancation Technology 10/08/2020

Jakarta, 29/06/1997

10:001/20:00
Terobredieni Berdenerkon Kajannum Bailar Afraduus, Nasional Pergurum Tinggi Kenesterino Pradsikkan dan Kebadasuan Republik Indonesia Nasional Pergurum Tinggi Kenesterino Pradsikkan dan Kebadasuan Republik Indonesia di 10:042020 Nasional Pradsikan Sajandari Pradsikan Sajand

ijazah kri diserabkan setelah yang bersangkutan memenuhi serma pernyaratan yang ditentukan dan kepadanya dilimpuhkan segala memenang dan hat yang berhabangan dengan ijazah yang dimilikinya, seria berhat memakai gater akademil. Sarjama Komputer (S.Kom.) On bening fallified alf the abjudyad engalement, the observersationed has been assurded this sendicate with all the authorities and rights perfolong to it need the right to bear the academic degree. Benchelor of Computer Science.

Rektor, Asctor,

Prof. Dr. Sumaryote



Johanna, 12/08/2020 Johanna

Mym Ir. Snepardi Harris, M.T.



### TRANSKRIP SEMENTARA

Fokultus - Teknik dan limu Kemputar Prog. Studi - Teknik Informatika NPM - 201643502079 Namu - Akmal Rivai

Sanu Aknal Rivai Tempot/Tgl. Lihir : Jakarta, 29 Juni 1897

a lounge day of	287/98/22/00/22/24/29/00	525	507	A Section Section	reserve reserves	310	043
1. MKK-D101	Pengantar Teknologi Informosi	2	A-	1. MCH-0201	Sistem Digital	3	11-
2. MKK-D102	Algoritus 1 *)	2	B-	2. MKK-D20)	Algoritms 2 *) %)	13	B
3 MKK-D104	Pertrogramme ( #)	2	B-	3. MKK-D005			6.
4. MKK-D108	Bebesa Inggris I	2	11-	4. MKK-D209		2	9
5. MKK-D115	Kolkules (*)	2	B.	5. MKK-D216		2	H
6. MKK-DH9	Enrika Duscr I	3	Bi		Fisika Ossar 2	2	H H
7 MPK-D101	Pondidikon Agame I	2	-	7. MKK-D221	Logica Matoeratiko	2	0.55
8. MPK-E107	Bohosa Indonesia I	*	A.	8. MPK-D202	Pendidikan Agama 2	2	4
Souceter 2				Semister 4			
L KB43F346	Suringen Komputer *) #)	3	Bi	1. KB43F425	Arsibektus dan Organisasi Komputer *J	3	10
2 KK40F09	Statistika Dasar	3	CI	2. KB431415	Sistem Hases Data *)	2	11
1 KK43F321	Struktur (Tota *)	2	Cit	3. KB431436	Praktikum Sistem Basis Data #1	1	A
4 KK43F322	Prokrikum Stroktor (brin #)	1	H+	4: KK437433	Alphur Linice dan Matrik *)		110
5 KK40F324	Sistem Informed	3	1114	5. KK430434	Manajemen Proyek	3	31
6. KK43F330	Pentregramos 3 %	3	B-	6. KK43F448	Metode Namerik	3	47
7. KK43F339	Kulkulin 3	2	A-	7. PK43F402	Pend. Precede dan Kowerganggaran	3	B
8. KK49F347	Matematike Dekrit	3	B	A. PK43F406	Sejasah Perjuangan dan Juti Diri PGRI	2	11
Semester 5				Semester 6			
1. BINOF503	Data Sessel dan Badaya Dasar	20	A-	1. BBOSIST	Komputer des Moyarakat	2	n
2 BB43E532	Keeskapus Autorpersonal (Interpresental Skill)	2	A.	2. KB43F643	Fernrogeaman Web 2 (1)	3	B
3 KB430531	Perrograman Bermentawi Objek	3	C	J. KB43F645	Analisa dan Person: Sistem Informaci *)	1	11
4 KB43F540	Sistom Openes *)	3	10+	4. KB437649	Interaksi Marassa dan Komputer *)		11
5. KB43F541	Teori Bahasa dan Actomita *)	3	A-	5. KB43F650	Telouk Kompilani*)	7	C
6 KB43F547	Partrograman Web 1 #1	3	A-	6. KK410644	Pertrogramas Visual #)	3.8	11
7. KK43F520	Statistika Lunjut	2	B	T. PB43F618	Bioeis Infirmatika	2 2	H
8. PB43F509	Kewirsusaksan	2	A	8. PK43F614	Penulinan Troish	2	A
Securitor 7				Semaster 8			
1 BB43G754	Rekayosa Perangkat Lurak 40 *)	3	A-	1. KB49G861	Janiagen Syacof Terrore ()	2	$\mathbf{n}$
2. HB43GTS5	Risci Operasional	3	A-	1 KH430863	Pangolohus Cirra (611)	3.36	A
1. KH430752	Kawanan Kongster	2	51-	3. KB430875	Kolinir Korja Proktik (KKP) #	7	11-
4. KB436753	Komputer Grafik *) #3	3	A	4. KB43G877	Tingus Alibir	6	B
5. KB43G789	E-Consumerce (FF)	2	111				
6. KB43G760	Sistem Burbesis Pongetofeam +)	2	A				
7. PB43G756	Etika Profesi	2 2	Λ-				
	Fillsafet films	-	FR:				

Iskartz, 16 Februari 2021 Ka Biro Adri: Akademik,

Hardau Marsito, S.E., M.Pd.

# **PROVINSI JAWA BARAT** KOTA DEPOK

: 3276022906970004 NIK

: AKMAL RIVAL

Tempat/Tgl Lahir: JAKARTA, 29-06-1997

Jenis kelamin : LAKI-LAKI Gol, Darah :Alamat : PALSIGUNUNG
RT/RW : 007/001
Kel/Desa : TUGU
Kecamatan : CIMANGGIS

Agama : ISLAM

Status Perkawinan: BELUM KAWIN

Pekerjaan PELAJAR/MAHASISWA

Kewarganegaraan: WNI

Berlaku Hingga : SEUMUR HIDUP



KOTA DEPOK 28-10-2015

POLRI DAERAH METRO JAYA RESORT METRO DEPOK SEKTOR CIMANGGIS Jl. Raya Jakarta - Bogor Km 33 Telp. 021.8741483 Nomor: 09-0607924



# SURAT KETERANGAN CATATAN KEPOLISIAN POLICE RECORD Nomor: SKCKYANMAS/ 2.854 / II. /YAN 2.3./2021 /SEK CMG

Otomorçkan bersama ini bahwa : This is to certify that Nama Mama Jeris Kolamin Sex

AKMAL RIVAL

: LAKI-LAKI

INDONESIA

Kebangsaan Nationally

: ISLAM

Assama
Religion
Tempat dan tot lahir
Place and date of birth
Tempat linggal sekarang
Cerrent address

: JAKARTA, 29 JUNI 1997 : PALSIGUNUNG RT 07/01 KEL, TUGU

KEC. CIMANGGIS KOTA DEPOK

Pekerjaan Occupation

Nomor Kartu Tanda Penduduk Cdizens card number

: 3276022906970004

Citizens card number
Nomor PasperKITAS/KITAP\*
PassporWITAS/MITAP number
Rumus Edik lati
Fingerprots Formula
Saletah diadakan penetilan hinosa saat dikeluarkan surat keterangan ini yang didasarkan kepada :
As of screening through the issue hereof by wirtle of:

Catatan Kepolisian yang ada Existing Police record

bahwa name tersebut diatas tidak memiliki calatan atau keteribatan dalam kegiatan kriminal apagun the bearer hursel proves not to be involved in any criminal cases

selama ia berada di Indonesia dari 29 JUNI 1997 during histher stay in Indonesia from sampil dengan 10 : 15 FEBRUARI 21

: 15 FEBRUARI 2021

Keterangan ini diberikan berhubungan dengan permohonan This certificate is issued at the request to the applicant

: MELAMAR PEKERJAAN

Umuk keperluan/menuju\* For the purpose Beriaku dari tanggal Valid Irom

: 15 FEBRUARI 2021

: 15 AGUSTUS 2021

CIMANGGIS

Sampti dengan 7o





This is to certify that

# **Akmal Rivai**

has completed

# **Python - Data Science**

on November 29th - December 24th, 2021 provided by Sanbercode.

Bandung, December 2021
Sanbercode CEO

Khairun Rizki

sanbercode



# SERTIFIKAT KEHADIRAN

diberikan kepada:

# Akmal Rivai

atas kehadirannya pada:

Event IBM Call4Code 2020 - Developer Roadshow Waktu 04 Mar 2020 08:30 s/d 04 Mar 2020 16:00

Bandung, 05 Mar 2020

DRemma

Narenda Wicaksono Chief Executive Officer Dicoding Indonesia



Scan QR Code di atas untuk mengakses portfolio Developer. Atau akses portfolio tersebut melalui link berikut: https://www.dicoding.com/users/685002/events





# **Certificate** of Completion

this certifies to

# **Akmal Rivai**

has successfully completed

"Belajar Automation Testing untuk Buka Peluang Karir QA Engineer"

02 August 2022

Alamanda Shantika Santoso CEO of Binar Academy





THIS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT

# **Akmal Rivai**

Software Quality Assurance Tester Automation User Interface Testing

Sept 02 - Oct 08, 2022

Barru Kurniawan

Credential ID : SQA-AUITJQ1063





THIS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT

# **Akmal Rivai**

Software Quality Assurance Tester
Automation API Testing

Sept 02 - Oct 08, 2022

Barru Kurniawan

Credential ID: SQA-AATJQ1063





THIS ACKNOWLEDGES THAT

# **Akmal Rivai**

Software Quality Assurance Tester

Manual API Testing

March 05 - Apr 07, 2022

Barru Kurniawan

Credential ID: SQA-MATJQ1063